JAMES PUELLMANN

james@puellmann.net · resume.puellmann.net 268 E. Broadway, New York, NY 10002 · (314) 307-7435

Summary

Senior infrastructure engineer, DevOps advocate, Agile veteran, Certified Scrum Master, and Linux enthusiast.

Extensive experience in tech leadership, system architecture, project and program management roles across diverse industries including Web Media, Publishing, E-Commerce, Finance, Energy, Government, IT Managed Services, IT consulting, healthcare, and software development.

Broad experience in DevOps Best Practices, Linux operating system build and deployment, container orchestration, infrastructure as code, configuration management and workflow automation for CI/CD pipelines.

Proven team leader, mentor, and teacher.

Skills & Technical Proficiencies

Computing Platforms: Amazon AWS, Microsoft Azure, Kubernetes, Tanzu Kubernetes, VMware

Terraform, Pulumi, CloudFormation, AzureRM, Bicep Infrastructure as Code:

Configuration Management: Ansible, Chef, Puppet

CI/CD: Azure DevOps, Gitlab CI, GitHub Actions, Jenkins

Operating Systems: Ubuntu Linux, Fedora Linux, RHEL and CentOS Linux, Debian Linux

Docker, Git, Helm, Packer, Vagrant, Hashicorp Vault, Python Other:

Experience

World Wide Technology

Lead DevOps Engineer

New York, NY Oct 2017 - Feb 2024

- DevOps Engineer
- Leader, Internal DevOps Practice
- · Tech Mentor
- · Tanzu Kubernetes Practice Lead
- DevOps Engineering Consultant
- Delivery Engineer

The New York Times

Lead Engineer, Infrastructure

New York, NY Jun 2013 - Oct 2017

- · Infrastructure deployment and administration
- Software Repository and Patch Deployment Systems
- · Standardized OS Image Provisioning
- · Automation and Modernization of Legacy Software Systems
- Configuration Management and Continuous Software Integration

CenturyLink (as Savvis)

Program Manager

New York, NY and St. Louis, MO Oct 2006 - Jun 2013

- Program Manager, AMC Networks
- Systems Architect, PR Newswire
- · Technical Operations Manager, Hallmark Cards
- Technical Operations Manager, American Stock Exchange
- · Sr. Systems Engineer, American Stock Exchange

St. Louis, MO **Unisys** Nov 2002 - Oct 2006

Sr. Linux Administrator, USDA Web Farm

• Sr. Linux Engineer and Linux Subject Matter Expert for USDA Web Farm

System Administration: Linux, Apache, Tomcat, HP-UX

Amdocs St. Louis, MO Jun 2000 - Oct 2002 Configuration Control Administrator

Team Lead, Amdocs Infrastructure Configuration and Control Group

Lead DevOps Engineer, WWT Loyalty Program for Global Retail Chain

(Terraform, Microsoft Azure, Azure DevOps, Amazon AWS)

Led Infrastructure and DevOps efforts for a team of 30+ developers to rebuild a customer loyalty platform for a global retail chain.

Designed and implemented IaC and full CI/CD pipeline for ten software repositories to deploy new architecture into Azure and integrate with legacy AWS deployments.

DevOps Engineer, WWT Website Deployment for Medical Device Manufacturer

(Terraform, Ansible, Microsoft Azure, Azure DevOps)

Architected and deployed IaC and CI/CD Pipeline for new Azure cloud architecture to host website and CMS application for medical device manufacturer.

Consulting DevOps Engineer, WWT Azure Migration for Regional Bank

(Microsoft Azure, Azure DevOps, Terraform, Ansible)

Consulted as Subject Matter Expert on DevOps, IaC, and CI/CD for a large regional bank's migration to the Azure cloud.

Practice Lead, WWT Tanzu Kubernetes Platform Services Offering

(VMware Tanzu Kubernetes Grid (TKG), Kubernetes, Terraform, Ansible, Helm, VMware ESX, Amazon AWS) Led technical execution for Tanzu Kubernetes Product offering as partnership between WWT and VMware. Architected, installed and configured Kubernetes clusters and consulted with client technical and executive roles on ongoing cluster administration.

DevOps Engineering Consultant, Multiple WWT Clients

(The Three Ways, Theory of Constraints, The Five Pillars, Kaizen, Lean, Kanban, Scrum)

Assess client engineering teams to identify and evaluate DevOps practices strengths and weaknesses.

Develop executive strategies for enhancing DevOps excellence within IT organizations.

Embed within client infrastructure and software engineering teams to improve DevOps workflow by teaching, mentoring, and leading by example.

Delivery Engineer, WWT Microservices Replatform for National Retail Chain

(Kubernetes, KOPS, Helm, Amazon AWS, Ansible, Terraform, GitLab CI, Packer, Docker, Jenkins, PostgreSQL)

Design and build vanilla Kubernetes environment in AWS for retail chain restaurant online ordering system. Implement all IaC and end-to-end CI/CD pipelines for Kubernetes infrastructure and AWS cloud environments.

Lead Engineer: Infrastructure, The New Yoark Times

(Terraform, Puppet, Packer, Vault, Git, Python, Travis, Jenkins, Postgres)

Designed and built single, standardized OS image for deployment across three infrastructure platforms.

Designed and built CI/CD pipelines and automated testing platform for same.

Built initial POC infrastructure for service migration to GCP cloud.

Awards & Recognition

High Performing Employee Practice Lead for Tanzu Kubernetes product offering. High Performing Team Award DevOps Consultant for high profile credit union consulting project. High Performing Team Award DevOps Consultant for Agile & DevOps adoption program at a credit union. High Performing Team Award Delivery Engineer for large retail chain website redesign.		Mar, 2022			
		Feb, 2021 Nov, 2020 Jan, 2019			
			Education and Certifications		
			Bachelor of Science, Mathematics	University of Missouri - Columbia	May, 2000
Education and Certifications					
DUCE 904005027914524: Jun 2009	Cartified Carum Macter Corum Alliance: Con 2	0017			

RHCE 804005037814534: Jun, 2008 Certified Scrum Master, Scrum Alliance: Sep, 2017 GitLab Solutions Architect: Dec, 2020 HashiCorp Certified Terraform Associate: Jul, 2021